# **Aly Fluckey**

I am a front-end focused developer with a passion for design systems, usability and inclusivity. With over 10 years of experience in software development, UX and consulting, I am a skilled communicator and enjoy working with teams to build products that address actual human needs.

Chicago, IL

fluckeya@gmail.com

Website

Phone available by request

#### **EXPERIENCE**

## **Thinkspan**, **LLC**, remote — Senior Software Engineer

July 2020 - PRESENT

Mobile development using React Native, Flow, Storybook, Jest

Shipped a production-ready <u>iOS app</u> to the App Store from concept to completion in only 3 weeks

Standardized our component library - currently supporting multiple production applications

Developed and documented our Design System using Storybook

Designed and implemented dramatic improvements to the development lifecycle resulting in greater transparency, higher quality products and increased velocity

### **MariaDB**, remote — Lead Front End Developer

May 2019 - PRESENT

Led front end development for the Database as a Service product, SkySOL, using the ServiceNow platform

Developed and delivered customized portal web pages and widgets in ServiceNow using AngularJS, Bootstrap

Educated team about benefits of design systems, modern front end methodologies and data-driven design

# **Table XI,** Chicago, IL — Front End Practice Lead

December 2015 - April 2019

Established and led a 6-member practice of Front End Developers

Led front end development on over 25 client projects

Resigned and rebuilt The Spice House's e-commerce site, resulting in increased revenue by 35%

Utilized Google Design Sprints, user research and validation to define features and functionality, better ensuring that we are <u>solving the right problems</u>

#### **TECHNOLOGIES**

JavaScript, React, React Native, Stimulus, Vue, AngularJS HTML, CSS, SCSS Ruby, Ruby on Rails Git, GitHub, GitLab Styled Components Craft CMS ServiceNow

#### SPECIAL SKILLS

Consulting, communication
Design Systems
Project Management
Agile, Lean methodologies
Debugging
Browser compatibility
Wireframing, prototyping
Sketch, Figma, Invision
User Research
Information Architecture

#### **EXTRA CURRICULAR**

Windy City Rails

Speaker: <u>Delightful Stylesheets</u>

Tech Done Right Podcast
Building Large CSS Apps And
Components

DevBootcamp

Mentoi

Speaker: Design 101, Front End

## **2Checkout**, Chicago, IL — Lead Front End Developer

April 2015 - November 2015

Redefined design system with an emphasis on responsive, reusable components that were cross-browser compatible

Established and communicated front end practices to larger development team

# **Falafel Software**, Remote — Front End Developer

August 2014 - March 2015

Created toolbox of reusable CSS animations to be used across a number of client projects

Built responsive user interfaces based on high-resolution mockups

## **Neo Innovation**, Columbus, OH — *Developer*, *Designer*

November 2012 - August 2014

Contributed to application development for a variety of clients using Ruby on Rails, JavaScript, Haml and Scss

Consulted with clients to gather requirements and validate ideas using agile and lean methodologies

#### **EDUCATION**

## **Drake University**, Des Moines, IA — *Graphic Design*

August 2008 - May 2010

Tips and Tricks

Girl Develop It

Chapter Organizer (Columbus) Instructor: Intermediate HTML5/CSS3 and Responsive Design TA for HTML/CSS Intro and

Intermediate classes